let's roll
[Music]
hi guys we're group 12 I'm Ashley hi I'm
Jeffrey hi this is a blush hi hi this is
argument our video is going to discuss
speaking technologies in the real estate
industry in an age before smartphone
people were forced to wander the streets
and looking for houses to buy or to
reach it was a hopeless tough with
everyone relying on newspapers or
word-of-mouth
houses were nearly impossible to find
and as an owner hadn't put up a sign
outside it made the task even more
difficult customers were left feeling
dejected sad and helpless as they
wandered around aimlessly trying to find
these phantom houses this all changed
with seeking technology so what is
speaking technology a lighthouse things
are signal of light to communicate with
ship similar to this a beacon users a
Bluetooth low-energy signal to
communicate with any smart device in
this range this is Marc Marc is looking
for a house Marc got a notification to
say that there were three houses for
sale in this street so he decided to
beat you down and have a look as Marc
nears one of the houses that are for
sale the beacon registers that come on
with our app has approached and sends
him a push notification with details
about the property that is for sale
there are many devices that can be used
to broadcast the beacons such as
computers tablets smartphones or USBs
Dinkins can be used in a variety of
different places such as amusement parks
schools airports retail houses stadiums
hotels museums and even restaurants we
designed our app using beacon technology
for the real estate market
our app is called hi or house and great
head real estate agencies give us their
property information and then we provide
them without interactive app and the use
of beacon technology in our new digital
age customers can now use beacon
technology and their smartphones to find
houses to buy or to rent at the top of
the street customers get a notification
from our app to say that there are
houses to fail through the down the
street as they continue down the street
the beacon located in a house that is
for sale triggers a notification in our
house in great hands at the app and
provides information about the property
we get access to the Realtors
information pictures of the house and
other properties for sale in the area
and it gives the customers the
opportunity to book a viewing of the
house at a later date there are several
speakers of our app for customers
firstly customers will receive a push
notification when they near a house with
their selected criteria the app is
available on all smart devices and is
easy to install and to operate customers
can enjoy down the street and they will
receive a notification when they
approach a house sale or for rent
using beacons and side houses will allow
for customers to view houses at earthen
homes without a real estate agent
following them around as the beacons
will provide information about specific
rooms and features the Apple has an
interactive map which lists all of the
properties that are registered with our
software finally the app will provide a
much more interactive experience for the
customer which will make the job of
house hunting more enjoyable
[Music]