introducing ibeacons
so what is it let me take you through it
picture a lighthouse a lighthouse send
the signal of light to communicate with
ships similar to a lighthouse a beacon
uses a Bluetooth low-energy signal to
communicate with any smart device in its
range simple right
let's talk hardware there are many
devices that can be used to broadcast as
a beacon such as a computer iPad USB and
iPhone there's plenty of options to suit
your own personal needs
once broadcasting you get the micro
location of device in the vicinity of a
beacon which is much more accurate than
a satellite struggling to get a precise
GPS location all the way from space it's
amazing how beacons are activated just
by walking nearby let's look for example
you could be out for a stroll when your
phone gets a notification from a nearby
store it's enticing so you go in to
check it out
upon entering an employee greets you as
you make your way around the story you
notice a product you really like beacon
recognizes you're near the product and
deliver the coupon straight to your
phone I check out your phone or skin
redeeming your coupon this completes
your purchase
on the way out the store offers you a
discount upon returning motivating you
to come back how cool is that
three main things happen here the
offline physical location digital online
attraction and the resulting action
offline or we like to say offline online
to offline it's about the real world not
just the digital one so where can I be
can be used it can be used in retail
transportation restaurants homes hotels
museums stadiums schools and even
amusement parks essentially you can use
ibeacon anywhere