as I said earlier our vision for our
system is to help you get things done it
turns out a big part of getting things
done it's making a phone call you may
want to get an oil change schedule maybe
call a plumber in the middle of the week
or even schedule a haircut appointment
you know we are working hard to help
users through those moments we want to
connect users to businesses in a good
way businesses actually rely a lot on
this but even in the u.s. 60% of small
businesses don't have an online booking
system set up we think hey I can help
with this problem so let's go back to
this example let's say you want to ask
Google to make you a haircut appointment
on Tuesday between 10:00 and noon what
happens is the Google assistant makes
the call seamlessly in the background
for you so what you're going to hear is
the Google assistant actually calling a
real salon to schedule the appointment
for you let's listen or what time are
you looking for well at 12 p.m. we do
not have a false p.m. available but
closest we have to that is a 1:15 do you
have anything between 10 a.m. and 12
p.m. depending on what service she would
like what service is she looking for
just a woman's haircut for now ok we
have a 10 o'clock 10:00 a.m. is fine
okay what's her first name the first
name is Lisa I'll say perfect so I will
see we thought 10 o'clock on May 3rd ok
great have a great day
[Applause]