he was dictating part of the message
versus when she was asking it to
complete an action thanks thank you
thanks right on your phone we're
envisioning a paradigm shift this next
generation assistant will instantly
operate your phone with your voice
multitask across apps and complete
complex actions all with nearly zero
latency and actions like turning on the
flashlight opening Gmail or checking
your calendar will even work offline now
it's a very hard problem within solving
and I'm really excited to share the
realization of this vision is not far
off in fact this next generation
assistant is coming to the new pixel
phones later this year this is the best
way to get things done you just saw them
making it much faster but it also has to
be personal enough to really help you
our first life helps especially
important in areas where people's
preferences completely different like
choosing what to listen to what to do on
the weekend or even like to eat let's
look at a recipe example people what
should I cook for dinner
here are some recipe pics for you now as
you can see the assistant picked recipes
tailored to me for example it suggested
a bourbon chicken recipe because it's
healthy with barbecue recipes in the
past
and what it really love is that
different people get completely
different results we call this feature
fix for you and a relaunching of smart
displays later this summer
starting with recipes podcasts and
events now there are your preferences
becoming more personal means the
assistant will better understand the
people places and events that are
important to you now one important
person in my life is my mom I'm going to
visit right after i/o so let's say I ask
my assistant how's the traffic to mom's
house don't understand what I need buy
warm socks right welcome in Toledo mom
stops wait a minute this place a
non-profit childcare center in other
cities mom's house can be a restaurant
or grocery store in fact there's lots of
things in the world of moms housing now
in linguistics the process of figuring
out which thing a phrase refers to is
called reference resolution and it's
fundamental to understanding human
language and people we approach this
problem using our knowledge track of
things in the world and their
relationships it's what allows us to
understand something like the Starbucks
near the Golden Gate Bridge
today we're expanding the assistants
ability to understand youth better by
applying those same techniques to the
things in your world we call it personal
references so if I share my mom's
contact info with the assistant I can
ask people what's the weather like at
Mom's house this weekend Friday and
Saturday and Carmichael will be partly
cloudy
how long will take to get there with
light traffic it will take you 2 hours
and 14 minutes to get to 123 Main Street
by car remind me to order flowers you
make before mom's birthday all right
I'll remind you on July 3rd and it goes
beyond mom if you're sharing 30 people
places and events with the assistant
you'll be able to ask for things more
naturally like show me photos of my son
or directions to the restaurant
reservation or remind me to pick up
chocolates on my anniversary and rest
assured you're always in control you can
edit or delete this information at any
time in the updated View tab and
assistant settings now in place where
the assistant can be especially helpful
is in the car
offering a safer hands-free way to get
everything you need while you're on the
road now we've been focused on the main
things that you all want when we're
driving to get what we're going safely
to catch up with friends and listen to
something interesting along the way last
year we got the assistant to Android
auto and earlier this year we added in
to navigation in Google Maps I'm happy
to share the assistant is also coming
two ways in the next few weeks now I'd
like to show you the future of how we're
improving our mobile driving experience
even more introducing the assistance new
driving mode just put your phone in the
car and say hey people let's drive
driving mode has a thoughtfully designed
dashboard that brings your most relevant
activities front and center while you're
driving and includes suggestions
personalized for you for example if you
have a dinner reservation on your
calendar will see a convenient shortcut
to navigate to the restaurant or if you
started a podcast at end in the morning
once you get in your car it'll display a
shortcut to resume the episode right
where you left off town also pilots off
contacts
I think easier to call them
and recommendations for other things to
listen to that once you're navigating
phone calls and music appear in a
low-profile way so you can get things
done without leaving your navigation
screen a google play some jazz sure
check out this jazz music station on
YouTube music now everything is voiced
in a game so football comes in the
assistant will tell you who's calling
and ask if you want to answer without
having to take your eyes off or call for
mom do you want to pick it up no thanks
thanks for your help with the demo mom
alright it's the best of all with the
assistant already on your phone there's
all kinds of tasks whether they are at
home or on the go but we want to build
and even more helpful assistant in order
to process peachtree we rely on complex
algorithms it includes multiple machine
learning models one model Maps incoming
sound bites into phonetic units another
one takes and assembles these phonetic
units into words and then a third model
predicts the likelihood of these words
in the sequence there are so complex
that they require 100 gigabytes of
storage and a network connection
bringing these models to your phone
think of it as putting the power of a
Google Data Center in your pocket it's
an incredibly challenging computer
science problem I'm excited to share we
reached a significant milestone further
advances in deep learning have allowed
us to combine and shrink the hundred
gigabyte models down to half a gigabyte
small enough to bring it onto mobile
devices this Sirleaf network latency and
makes the assistants so much faster so
fast
that happened to use your phone would
see slow I think this is going to
transform the future of the assistant
and I'm thrilled to bring Scott to tell
you more about our next generation
assistant what if we could bring the AI
that powers the assistant right on your
phone what if the assistant was so fast
at processing your voice that tapping
operator phone would almost seem slow it
opens up many of you spaces and we want
to show you how fast it is internally
we've been calling this the
next-generation assistant running on
device it can process an understand
requests in real time and deliver the
answers up to ten times faster now make
ease here and she's gonna help us test
it out starting with some back-to-back
commands to demonstrate its speed on
this demo
it's hot off the press so please send
your positive energy over a neg ease
Direction open calendar open calculator
open photos
set a timer for 10 minutes what's the
weather today what about tomorrow show
me John Legend on Twitter get a lift
drive it to my hotel
turn the flashlight on turn it off take
a selfie alright now as you can see
and now the gatehouse instantly now you
met a person to notice that with
continued conversation she was able to
make several requests in a row without
having to say hey evil each time now we
all have an effortless way to operate
your phone you can start to imagine how
the assistant used into the device could
orchestrate pass across apps let's look
at another demo worm that he's chatting
with a friend he's gonna ask her about a
recent trip noticed how easy it is for
her to respond their voice and even
share a photo
reply had a great time with my family
and it was so beautiful
show me my photos from Yellowstone the
ones with animals
send it to Justin
[Music]
all right ask you a question and you
need to look up the information you
respond Justin wanted to know when begi
spider eyes Wednesday flight Wednesday
slight
reply I should get it around 1:00 p.m.
so notice how it helped Maggie multitask
more easily across different apps save
her a lot of back-and-forth now you can
even imagine this next generation
assistant handling more complex speech
scenarios like composing and sending an
email hey Google send an email to
Jessica hi Jessica I just got back from
the other zone and completely fell in
love with it sent subject to Yellowstone
adventures let me know the next weekend
works for dinner so I can tell you all
about it send it now as you can see this
required the assistant to understand
when they all need to download an app to
start driving dragon Road will be
available this summer on any Android
phone with the assistant billion devices
in over 30 languages across e countries
and with duplex on the web the next
generation assistance personalized help
and assistance in the par we're
continuing to build on our mission to be
the fastest most personal way to help
you get these done now before I go I
want to share a little something that a
lot of
I've been asking for check this out
[Music]
just by saying spa don't hate you leave
it
and it's rolling out on smart displays
and Google homes and english-speaking
look house starting today
[Applause]
you